<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>hnrss</title><link>https://www.ilijason.se/hnrsum.xml</link><description>Description</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 10:06:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ask HN: Machine learning engineers, what do you do at work?</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40610794</link><description>Machine learning engineers collaborate with non-technical people to create models using large amounts of data, often in the healthcare field. They spend time in meetings, preparing data, and analyzing data to forecast outcomes. Despite concerns about data security, access to information is readily available. Some engineers have had experiences where training documentation directed them to send SQL queries to production without proper permissions.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40610794"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 17:26:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Sound of Water: Matsuo Basho and the Old Pond</title><link>https://inquiringmind.com/article/2602_32_mcmahon/</link><description>Could not parse target.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40603967"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why are debut novels failing to launch?</title><link>https://www.esquire.com/entertainment/books/a60924704/debut-fiction-challenges/</link><description>Debut novels are struggling to succeed in the competitive book market, and there are various reasons for this trend.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40612321"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 19:57:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LedgerStore Supports Trillions of Indexes at Uber</title><link>https://www.uber.com/blog/how-ledgerstore-supports-trillions-of-indexes/?uclick_id=67d612cb-12f8-470a-98fd-e9f7144dfafb</link><description>Could not parse target.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40609326"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 14:55:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Le vieux Paris n'est plus</title><link>https://davidabell.substack.com/p/le-vieux-paris-nest-plus</link><description>The text "Le vieux Paris n'est plus" by David A. Bell discusses the changing nature of Paris and how the old city is disappearing. It reflects on the transformation of the city and the loss of its historical charm.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40593707"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 05:05:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenSSH introduces options to penalize undesirable behavior</title><link>https://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article;sid=20240607042157</link><description>OpenSSH has introduced new options in sshd(8) to penalize undesirable behavior and shield specific clients from penalties. The new options, PerSourcePenalties and PerSourcePenaltyExemptList, monitor client behavior and penalize them for repeated unsuccessful authentication attempts or causing sshd to crash. PerSourcePenalties will be enabled by default in the upcoming OpenBSD 7.6 release. Admins need to be aware of the consequences of inconsiderate NAT use when using these options.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40610621"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 17:08:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boeing Passenger Jet Nearly Crashes Because of Known Software Bug</title><link>https://www.independent.co.uk/travel/tui-boeing-flight-bristol-disaster-avoided-b2558536.html</link><description>A disaster was narrowly avoided as a plane cleared the runway just seconds before a potential collision.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40615786"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 06:52:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tom 7: Badness 0 (Three ways)</title><link>http://tom7.org/bovex/</link><description>The text discusses different ways to access and experience the latest installment of Badness 0, including reading Knuth's Version and Epsom's Version in the SIGBOVIK 2024 proceedings, ensuring proper display in Chrome, and bathing in the flashing lights of Badness 0. It also mentions accessing the source code for a direct experience of "BUG" and provides information on compiling and using it. Additionally, the text mentions the availability of the source code under the GPL or GJPL licenses and promotes the author's YouTube channel and blog for further content.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40608332"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 13:01:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tokyo's Government Is Building Its Own Dating App to Combat Falling Birthrates</title><link>https://time.com/6986142/japan-tokyo-government-dating-app-marriage/</link><description>The Tokyo government is starting a matchmaking service to increase marriage rates.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40615953"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 07:34:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VGG Specs: Next-Gen Cross-Platform Vector Graphics with Advanced UI Effects</title><link>https://github.com/verygoodgraphics</link><description>The text is a script tag with attributes for crossorigin, defer, type, and src, linking to a JavaScript file on the GitHub website.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40599524"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 16:43:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Memory-safe, clean implementation of classic Posix "BC" calculator</title><link>https://github.com/rustcoreutils/posixutils-rs/tree/main/calc/src</link><description>The text is a script tag that references an external JavaScript file from GitHub's assets. The script is set to defer loading and is marked as anonymous.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40614467"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 01:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Slow-spinning radio neutron star breaks all the rules</title><link>https://www.sydney.edu.au/news-opinion/news/2024/06/05/slow-spinning-radio-neutron-star-breaks-all-the-rules.html</link><description>A slow-spinning radio neutron star discovered by the University of Sydney researchers defies conventional understanding of neutron stars.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40613312"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 21:46:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Replit used legal threats to kill my open-source project (2021)</title><link>https://intuitiveexplanations.com/tech/replit/</link><description>The author of the text, Radon, worked at Replit as an intern and later created an open-source project that allowed users to run code in various programming languages online. When he shared his project with Replit, they initially responded positively but later accused him of unethical behavior and stealing their design. Replit threatened legal action to shut down the project, citing their increased size and financial resources. After receiving an official response from Replit, Radon's project will be back up soon. The author questions why Replit would use legal threats to bully him into shutting down the project.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40615537"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 05:43:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Show HN: I created this land use visualisation for the Netherlands</title><link>https://koenvangilst.nl/labs/ons-land</link><description>This webpage uses hexagons to visualize land use in the Netherlands, with each hexagon representing 0.06% of the country's land. The color of each hexagon indicates a specific type of land use. Despite being densely populated, the Netherlands has a high number of solar panels, surpassing the entire continent of Africa.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40599763"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:02:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chebyshev approximation and how it can help (2012)</title><link>https://www.EmbeddedRelated.com/showarticle/152.php</link><description>The text discusses Chebyshev approximation and how it can help individuals save money, make friends, and influence people. It highlights the benefits of using this method and its practical applications in various aspects of life.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40614338"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:37:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Secret Hand Gestures in Paintings (2019)</title><link>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7233791/</link><description>Could not parse target.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40606924"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 09:36:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Show HN: Scipress.io – a Markdown writing platform like Notion Medium MkDocs</title><link>https://www.scipress.io/post/kehluzWG8Iq9y1Nu7IMP/docs</link><description>The text contains code related to the Scipress Docs website, including instructions for toggling the main menu open or closed. It also includes information on different sections of the website and their functionalities.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40608941"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 14:12:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yes, you can play Duck Hunt without a television (but I can't)</title><link>https://nicole.express/2024/no-screen-no-cpu-one-problem.html</link><description>The text discusses the history of Duck Hunt, a classic Nintendo game, and how it can be played without a television using a mechanical device from the 1970s. The device consists of a projector and a gun that requires specific batteries. It raises the question of whether it qualifies as a video game and describes the gameplay of shooting ducks projected onto a wall. The post also mentions a website with more information on the Nintendo mechanical Duck Hunt.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40612387"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 20:02:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3dfx Voodoo 4 video card in MXM format (2023)</title><link>https://www.vogons.org/viewtopic.php?t=100871</link><description>The text is discussing the Voodoo 4 M4800 graphics card and mentions the VOGONS website. It provides options for logging in or creating a new account on the site.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40613854"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 23:11:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LaTeX is the first PDF/UA-2 compliance accessible PDF producer</title><link>https://github.com/latex3/tagging-project/discussions/72</link><description>The text is a script tag that includes a JavaScript file from a specific URL on GitHub. It has attributes for crossorigin, defer, and type.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40587934"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 17:39:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Pole Water Infrastructure</title><link>https://brr.fyi/posts/south-pole-water-infrastructure</link><description>This post discusses the water infrastructure at the South Pole, where fresh water is produced from snow despite extreme temperatures. The author, an infrastructure enthusiast, shares details about the system and how it operates in such harsh conditions.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40615530"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 05:41:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Xv6, a simple Unix-like teaching operating system</title><link>https://pdos.csail.mit.edu/6.828/2023/xv6.html</link><description>Xv6 is a teaching operating system based on Unix V6, developed in 2006 and ported to RISC-V for the class 6.1810. The latest xv6 source code and text are available online. Feedback on using xv6 is welcomed, and suggestions for improvement can be sent to the course staff.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40613126"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 21:22:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A pure NumPy implementation of Mamba</title><link>https://github.com/idoh/mamba.np</link><description>The text is a script tag that links to an external JavaScript file on GitHub's assets server. The attributes crossorigin and defer are set to "anonymous" and "defer" respectively.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40594743"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 07:55:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Feynman’s Razor</title><link>https://defenderofthebasic.substack.com/p/feynmans-razor</link><description>Feynman's Razor is a concept discussed by the author Defender of the Basic. The concept likely involves the principles or ideas of physicist Richard Feynman.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40612285"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 19:53:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ASCII Silhouettify</title><link>https://meatfighter.com/ascii-silhouettify/</link><description>ASCII Silhouettify is an app that converts images into ASCII silhouettes using uniformly filled geometric shapes. It can only handle flat graphics with minimalistic, high-contrast forms and does not render shading or gradients. The app uses traditional ASCII characters for output and can be accessed through a browser or command-line. Users can choose different output formats such as colored text or HTML. The app supports multiple image formats and has options for customizing the output palette. Installation and uninstallation instructions are provided for different operating systems.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40610641"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Is PID 0?</title><link>https://blog.dave.tf/post/linux-pid0/</link><description>The text discusses the misconception around PID 0 in Unix systems. It explains that PID 0 does exist and is responsible for scheduling and power management, but is not shown to users through traditional APIs. The text criticizes the incorrect information found on the internet about PID 0, particularly stemming from a 16-year-old sentence on Wikipedia. It goes on to provide historical context and examples from Unix kernels to explain the role of PID 0 in different versions. It concludes by clarifying that PID 0 does not handle paging or virtual memory management as commonly believed.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40613287"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 21:42:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Own a weather station? We want your data</title><link>https://www.weather.gov/iln/cwop</link><description>The text is asking people who own weather stations to share their data. The data will be used for various forecasts including local, aviation, marine, rivers and lakes, hurricanes, severe weather, fire weather, sun/moon, long-range forecasts, climate prediction, and space weather. Additionally, past weather data and heating/cooling days are also of interest.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40589172"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 19:18:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What happened to Captura? OSS maintainer burnout (2023)</title><link>https://mathewsachin.github.io/blog/2023/04/09/captura-unmaintained.html</link><description>Captura was a screen capture app for Windows that allowed users to capture screen, webcam, audio, and keystrokes. The app is no longer maintained, but the source code is still available on GitHub. The creator, who started the project as a high school student, decided to stop providing updates due to burnout and threats from individuals selling the app under a different name without crediting him.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40615723"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 06:34:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Content Injection Attack on GitHub</title><link>https://github.com/younesbram/younesbram</link><description>The text is describing a JavaScript script tag with attributes crossorigin, defer, and src that is linking to a file on GitHub's assets server.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40615653"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 06:15:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apollo 8 astronaut William Anders ID'd in WA plane crash</title><link>https://www.fox13seattle.com/news/william-anders-wa-plane-crash</link><description>Apollo 8 astronaut William Anders has been killed in a plane crash in Washington state.
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40614227"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:16:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>